在宇宙最寒冷的地区 凶残的奥格都·杰哈德 混乱七神 沉睡在他们的水晶禁地之中
等待着重新掌控大地 焚毁天堂 德斯·维尔密斯传说 第87页
是什么使一个男人成为真正的男人呢?
What is it that makes a man a man?
是他的出身 他的本源?
Is it his origins, the way things start?
还是其它一些难以说清的东西呢?
Or is it something else, something harder to describe?
而对我来说 这一切始于1944年
For me, it all began in 1944.
在苏格兰海岸执行的一次秘密任务
Classified mission off the coast of Scotland.
纳粹们已经走投无路
The Nazis were desperate.
他们试图利用黑魔法和科学
Combining science and black magic...
打破战争的平衡
...they intended to upset the balance of the war.
我28岁时就已成为罗斯福总统的灵异现象顾问
I was 28, already a paranormal advisor to President Roosevelt.
但我从未想到那晚发生的事
I could never have suspected that what would transpire that night...
不仅改变了历史的进程
...would not only affect the course of history...
还永远改变了我的一生
...but change my life forever.
好啦 小伙子们
All right, men, let's go. Move!
(苏格兰 1944年10月9日)
我们上 上啊!
Come on! Come on! Come on!
分散开来
Let's fan it out.
你们的人
Your men...
他们需要这些
...they'll need these.
你是天主教徒吗?
Are you a Catholic?
是的 还有其他原因 不过这很难说清
Yes. Among other things. But that's hardly the point.
好吧 你需要这个东西
Well, you're gonna need one of these.
我痛恨使用暴力
l abhor the use of violence.
谢谢你 我希望你别把我当疯子 魏特曼士官
Thank you. l wouldn't want you to think me mad, Sergeant Whitman.
已经三天了 现在想这个太晚了 布隆姆教授
No, three days too late for that, Professor Broom.
小伙子们 出发吧!
All right, you guys, let's move, move, move, move!
小伙子们 上 上啊!
Come on boys, let's go!
这边走! 左面 右面!
This way! Left, right!
上啊 快啊!
Come on, men, let's get the lead out!
就要到了!
We're close!
你在浪费我们的时间 这岛上除了绵羊和岩石什么都没有
You're wasting our time. There's nothing here but sheep and rocks.
- 是遗迹 不是岩石 - 就在那里停下!
- Ruins, not rocks. - Hold it right here!
这是特隆德汉姆·阿比的遗迹 建在草地边界的交叉点上
The remains of Trondham Abbey, built on an intersection of ley lines...
这是人类世界和其他世界的边界
...the boundaries between our world and the others...
废话连篇!
What a load of crap!
见鬼 一周前 我还没听说过"反常现象"这个词
Hell, a week ago, l never even heard the word ''parabnormal.''
是灵异现象
Paranormal.
前进!
Move it!
保持阵型!
Hold the line.
来吧!
Come on!
天啊!
Sweet Jesus.
他们来此一定是为了绵羊?
They must be here for the sheep.
那个带防毒面具的怪物
The freak in the gas mask....
卡尔·卢布里切特·克鲁南
Karl Ruprecht Kroenen.
希特勒的头号杀手 北方神秘协会的头目
Hitler's top assassin and head of the Thule Occult Society.
如果他在这里 那比我想像的还要糟糕
lf he's here, this is worse than l thought.
不论今晚发生了什么...
No matter what happens tonight...
...这本书都会把你带回我身边
...this book will guide you back to me.
我不会离开你的
l will not leave you.
我将赐予你不朽的生命
l grant you everlasting life...
不褪的青春
...youth...
以及辅佐我的魔力
...and the power to serve me.
伊萨! 格里高利!
llsa! Grigori!
时间到了
lt's time.
五年的研究和建筑啊 格里高利!
Five years of research and construction, Grigori.
五年!
Five years!
元首不会容忍失败的
The fuhrer doesn't look kindly on failure.
将军 不会失败的
There will be no failure, general.
我向元首保证将有一个奇迹出现
l promised Herr Hitler a miracle.
我会带来一个奇迹
l'll deliver one.
我今晚所作的一切将永世流传!
What l will do tonight can never be undone!
我会打开地狱之门
l will open a portal...
唤醒奥格都·杰哈德
...and awaken the Ogdru Jahad:
混乱七神!
The Seven Gods of Chaos!
我们的敌人将被毁灭!
Our enemies will be destroyed!
废墟中
And from the ashes...
一个新的伊甸园将诞生
...a new Eden will arise.
卧倒!
Get down!
我只想拍张照片
l was taking a picture.
再拍我就砸掉你的像机!
You do that again and l'll carve you a new one.
听着 传送门已经打开了
Listen, the portal is open.
我们必须阻止他们
Do you understand? We have to stop them.
手雷! 手雷!
grenade! grenade!
冲啊! 冲啊!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
小心!
Look out!
趴下!
Get down!
差不多结束了!
lt's almost over.
不 还没有
No, it's not.
传送门打开的时间太长了
The portal's been open for too long.
可能有东西已经从那边过来了
Something may have come through.
让你手下彻底搜索整个区域
Have your men search the area thoroughly.
搜查那边!
Spread out over that way!
长官 这上面有东西!
Sir! Something up here!
他不见了
He's gone.
暂时而已
For now.
你说有些东西会过来
When you said something came through....
从哪里来?
From where?
我什么也没有看到!
l don't see them!
你真的相信地狱存在吗?
Do you really, really believe in hell?
那是一个黑暗的世界
There is a place, a dark place...
远古的魔鬼在那里沉睡 等待着回归
...where ancient evil slumbers and waits to return.
- 格里高利今晚让我们一窥地狱 - 格里高利?
- Grigori gave us a glance tonight. - Grigori?
那是俄国名字 对吧?
That's Russian, right?
格里高利·艾菲莫维奇·拉斯普亭
Grigori Efimovich Rasputin.
拉斯普亭?
Rasputin?
- 快说啊 - 俄国沙皇的神秘学顾问
- Come on! - Occult adviser to the Romanovs.
他在1916年的一次晚宴上
ln 1916, at a dinner in his honor...
被下毒 枪击 刀刺 棒打...
...he was poisoned, shot, stabbed, clubbed...
...阉割 最后沉湖
...castrated and finally drowned.
但我们今晚却看见了他
And yet, we saw him here tonight.
布隆姆教授
Professor Broom.
小心 小心点
Careful. Be careful.
- 那是个什么鬼东西? 猿猴吗? - 不是
- What the hell is that? An ape? - No.
是红色的 亮红色的
lt was red. Bright red.
把灯放低点 你吓到他了
Lower your light, you're scaring it.
- 你们两个在射击什么?  - 一只红色猿猴!
- What are you two shooting at? - A red ape!
不 不是猿猴
No, it's not an ape.
他手里有个大石头
lt's got a big stone in its hand.
我想那就是他的手
l think that is its hand.
那锤子怎么那么大啊!
Look at the size of that whammer.
不 等一下 等等!
No, wait! Wait!
给我件毯子
A blanket. Get me a blanket.
来啊 来啊 这很安全的
Come on. Come on. lt's safe.
跳下来
Jump down.
来啊 跳下来
Come on. Jump down.
是个男孩
lt's a boy.
只是个小婴孩
lt's just a baby boy.
往左一点
Move to the left.
就这样 我成为了一个怪胎的父亲
There we were, an unready father for an unwanted child.
我们在当晚就给他取了个名字
The boys gave him a name that very night.
回想起来 这名字并不好
In retrospect, perhaps not the most fortunate.
不过 我们也叫习惯了
But nevertheless, a name we all came to use.
我们叫他"地狱男爵"
We called him Hellboy.
看镜头
Look at the birdie.
关于他的起源有很多猜测
Speculation about the origins....
有证据说地狱男爵...
Evidence that Hellboy....
(联邦调查局和小怪物做交易)
那么 你说情报机关到底做了什么呢?
So, what is it exactly that you say this agency does?
我不骗你 它捕杀怪兽
I kid you not. It hunts monsters.
有人声称 这个生物...
The claim, of course, that this creature...
为联邦调查局工作 捕杀怪兽
...works for the FBI as a monster hunter.
《地狱男爵》
(摩尔达维亚 伯尔高山口　现代)
你们要找的在那里
What you seek is in there.
这是一个神圣的地方
This is a sacred place.
给我金子
Give me my gold.
我们不该来这里
We shouldn't be here.
主人
Master.
你的眼睛
Your eyes.
他们对你的眼睛做了什么?
What did they do to your eyes?
- 你告诉他了吗 - 还没
- Have you told him yet? - No.
(纽约 列克星敦肿瘤学中心)
我们该告诉他
We should.
恶性肿瘤
Malignant sarcoma.
在肺里
ln the lungs...
脊椎上
...the spine...
- 还有肝里 - 我大概...
- ...liver. - Approximately...
- 还能活多久? - 也许六个星期
- ...how long? - Maybe six weeks.
我可以替你安排住院治疗以缓解疼痛
l can arrange for hospitalization and pain management.
- 让你在最后时光好受些 - 不用了
- Make the time more bearable. - No.
我更愿待在家里
l'd rather be at home.
我还有一些事要安排
l have some arrangements to make.
为了我的儿子
For my son.
你可以随时来住院
You can always get a second opinion.
没必要了
That won't be necessary.
快点!
Hurry up!
- 快点! - 在这儿等着!
- Hurry up! - Wait right here!
汤姆·曼宁是联邦调查局特殊行动部的负责人
Tom Manning is the head of special operations at the FBI.
他今晚来我们演播室
He joins Pat in the studio tonight
谈谈最新的地狱男爵目击照片
to go over the latest Hellboy sighting.
这里 这就是尾巴
There. That's the tail.
而这些是角
And these are the horns.
我有个问题
l have a question.
(汤姆·曼宁 联邦调查局特殊行动部负责人)
这些异形 飞碟 雪人 地狱男爵的照片
In the pictures of aliens, UFO, the yeti, Hellboy...
为什么他们总对不准焦距?
...why is it they're always out of focus?
你干嘛不告诉我们
Why don't you tell us...
有关灵异现象研究和国家安全局的情况呢?
...about the Bureau of Paranormal Research and Defense?
我想告诉你 我想告诉全美公众一件事
l wanna tell you, l wanna tell the American public one thing.
什么局来着?
Now, this Bureau for the....
灵异现象研究和国家安全局
Paranormal Research and Defense.
根本不存在这个机构
There is no such thing.
(灵异现象研究和国家安全局 新泽西州 纽沃克)
"废物处理部门"?
“Waste Management Services”?
是谁?
What is it?
约翰·迈尔斯 联邦调查局的
John Myers, FBl.
从匡提柯总局调来的
Transfer from Quantico.
看镜头 孩子
Look at the birdie, son.
- 你好 我是约翰... - 你迟到了
- Hello. l'm John... - You are late. That's what you are.
- 迟了五分钟 - 是的 我知道
- Five minutes. - Yes, l know.
- 我要去... - 51区 我知道
- l'm going to... - Section 51 . l know.
小心你的手和肘
Watch your hands and elbows.
- 你说什么? - 小心你的手和肘
- Pardon? - Watch your hands and elbows.
有人吗
Hello?
请替我翻一页 如果你不介意的话
Turn the pages, please, if you don't mind.
请帮我
Please.
翻一页
The pages.
这些? 你在读这些?
These? You're reading these?
他一次读四本书 天天如此
Four books at once, every day...
只要我能在这里替他翻书
...as long as l'm there to turn the pages.
我叫布隆姆
My name's Broom.
特瑞沃尔·布隆姆
Professor Trevor Broom.
长官 我是约翰...
Sir, l'm John...
探员约翰·T·迈尔斯 1976年生于堪萨斯城
Agent John T Myers, Kansas City, '76.
T代表的是赛德尔斯 母亲的兄长
T stands for Thaddeus, mother's older brother.
十岁的时候下巴有了个疤痕
Scar on your chin happened when you were 10.
你还在指望有天它可以自动消失
You still wonder if it's ever going to fade away.
- 它怎么... - 是"他"
- How did it... - He.
不是"它"
Not ''it.''
亚伯拉罕·赛皮恩
Abraham Sapien.
在华盛顿圣特里南弃婴医院
Discovered alive in a secret chamber...
一个秘室中被发现
...of St. Trinian's Foundling Hospital, Washington.
他的名字是用...
His name was taken from this inscription...
他生活的水柜旁边的说明文字取的
...stuck to the side of his tank.
"伊斯欧·赛皮恩"
''lcthyo Sapiens.
"1865年4月14日"
April 14, 1865.''
亚伯拉罕·林肯死的那天
The day that Abraham Lincoln died.
因此我们都叫他艾比·赛皮恩
Hence, Abe Sapien.
腐烂的蛋
Rotten eggs.
很妙不是吗 艾比喜欢吃这个
A delicacy. Abe loves them.
他怎知道我这么多事?
How does he know so much about me?
艾比有个特殊的大脑额叶
Abe possesses a unique frontal lobe.
"特殊" 在这里你会常听到这词
''Unique.'' That's a word you'll hear frequently around here.
长官 我到底是在哪里?
Sir, where am l, exactly?
你进这房间时 该看到一句铭文
As you entered the lobby, there was an inscription:
"没有光明的地方 黑暗将大行其道"
''ln the absence of light, darkness prevails.''
夜里有些东西很活跃 迈尔斯探员
There are things that go bump in the night, Agent Myers.
绝对不要搞错这些
Make no mistake about that.
而我们就是反击那些家伙的人
And we are the ones who bump back.
1937年 希特勒参加了北方协会
1937, Hitler joins the Thule Society...
一群沉迷于神秘学的德国贵族建立的组织
...a group of German aristocrats obsessed with the occult.
1938年 他得到了朗基奴斯圣矛
1938, he acquired the Spear of Longinus...
就是那柄刺穿了主耶稣身体的圣矛
...which pierced the side of Christ.
持有圣矛的人会无敌于天下
He who holds it becomes invincible.
希特勒的权力增长了十倍
Hitler's power increases tenfold.
1943年 罗斯福总统决定反击
1943, President Roosevelt decides to fight back.
灵异现象研究和国家安全局就此诞生
The Bureau of Paranormal Research and Defense is born.
1958年 神秘学战争由于...
1958, the Occult Wars finally come to an end...
阿道夫·希特勒的死而结束了
...with the death of Adolf Hitler.
你是说1945年
1945, you mean.
希特勒是45年死的
Hitler died in '45.
是吗
Did he, now?
迈尔斯 这是克里探员
Myers, this is Agent Clay.
让他带你去吧
Take his lead.
他会向你做介绍的
He'll make the introductions.
你不来吗
You're not coming?
我亲手把你从70个大学毕业的新人中挑出来
l handpicked you from a roster of over 70 academy graduates.
别让我失望
Make me proud.
他们不会说的
They're not speaking.
布隆姆教授把他关起来了
Professor Broom had him grounded.
关起来? 谁被关起来了?
Grounded? Who's grounded?
好啦 你看到那鱼人了对吧?
Okay. You saw the fish guy, right?
是的 真奇怪
Oh, yeah. That was weird.
是吗 好吧
Yeah. Right.
好了 进来吧 见见其他家庭成员
Well, come on in. Meet the rest of the family.
他一天要吃六次
He gets fed six times a day.
喜欢猫
He's got a thing for cats.
你会是他的保姆 他的保护人 他最好的朋友
You'll be his nanny, his keeper, his best friend.
没人监护 他不许外出
He never goes out unsupervised.
谁?
Who?
我恨那些漫画书
l hate those comic books.
总是画错我的眼睛
They never get the eyes right.
地狱男爵
Hellboy.
他真的存在
He's real.
按照记录他已经60岁了
60 years old by our count.
不过他的年龄和我们的有所不同
But he doesn't age like we do.
想想看 狗就比我们活得短 他现在还没到二十
Think reverse dog years. He's barely out of his 20s.
你的头发怎么样 克里?
What's with the hair, Clay?
终于去植发了吧?
Finally got them implants, huh?
会长起来的
lt'll fill in.
这家伙是谁?
Who's the squirt?
迈尔斯探员是你的新联络员
Agent Myers is your new liaison.
我不想要他
l don't want him.
怎么回事 克里 你烦我了
What, you get tired of me, Clay?
那糖果 给他糖果
The candy. Give him the candy.
哦 先生 我...
Oh, sir, l....
我带了这个给你
l have these for you.
老爸回来了?
Father's back?
他还在生气?
He still angry?
是啊 你上次确实是逃跑了
Well, you did break out.
我只是想见她
l wanted to see her.
- 又不关其他人的事 - 但是 你又把自己弄上电视了
- Nobody's business. - lt is. You got yourself on TV again.
姓迈尔斯?
Myers, huh?
你有名字吗 迈尔斯
You got a first name, Myers?
不要盯着看 他不喜欢人盯着他看
Try not to stare. He hates it when people stare.
约翰 约翰·迈尔斯
John. John Myers.
呃 叫我约翰就行了
Well, John'll do.
- 不要盯着什么看? - 他的角 他把角挫平了
- Stare at what? - His horns. He files them to fit in.
约翰 你看什么呢?
What you looking at, John?
哦 没有 没什么 什么也没看
Oh, no, no, no. Nothing. Nothing at all.
红色警报
Code red.
Warning. Code red.
他们正找我们呢
They're playing our song.
来吧 冠军 我们去干掉一些怪兽吧
Come on, champ, let's go fight some monsters.
现在我们在麦肯图书馆
We're here at the Machen Library...
几小时前 这里的警报被触发了
...where just hours ago, an alarm was triggered.
纽约市警察对此还没有发布任何声明
The N.Y.P.D. has yet to issue a statement.
不过这里有特种部队装甲车 还有军医
We've got SWAT vans, paramedics. You name it.
而现在又开来辆垃圾车
And now here comes a garbage truck.
一辆巨大的垃圾车
A large garbage truck.
看这些丑陋的家伙 蓝鱼
Look at them ugly suckers, Blue.
我们和他们之间只隔一扇玻璃
One sheet of glass between them and us.
我一生都是这样的
Story of my life.
外面的世界 我终于可以出去了
Outside. l could be outside.
你是说 出去找她?
You mean, outside with her.
别找我的茬 哥们
Don't get psychic with me, fella.
没找你的茬
Nothing psychic about it.
放轻松点
You're easy.
我这样怎么能泡到妞? 开辆垃圾车来
How am l gonna get a girl? l drive around in a garbage truck.
丽兹把我们抛弃了 红大个
Liz left us, Red.
接受她的暗示吧
Take the hint.
我们才不接受什么暗示
We don't take hints.
到达目的地了
Civilians in bedroom.
好啦 兄弟们 我们把跟踪器同步一下
Okay, guys, let's sync up our locators.
把门封上 红大个和蓝鱼就要进来了
Seal the doors. Red and Blue are coming in.
19点整 警报被拉响
19 hours, an alarm was tripped.
报告说发现了一个大怪物 第五型的 极具攻击性
A large entity, type 5, reported. Very aggressive.
六名警卫已经被杀了
Six guards dead.
我想我们检查过这个地方
l thought we checked this place.
肯定是假警报
Fakes and reproductions.
很明显 不是什么东西都是假的
Apparently, not everything was fake.
父亲
Father.
怪物还在里面
The entity is still in there.
从监视器上可以看到 一座十六世纪的雕塑被破坏了
Video surveillance shows a 16th-century statue was destroyed.
大法官圣狄奥尼修斯的雕塑
St. Dionysius the Areopagite.
- 用来驱魔的雕像 - 正是
- Who wards off demons. - Exactly.
不过那个雕像 却是中空的
The statue, however, was hollow.
一个圣骨箱?
A reliquary.
一个囚室
A prison.
梵蒂冈认为它所囚禁的怪物极其危险
The Vatican deemed its occupant dangerous enough...
因此把它列入了亚维农名单 这名单我们也有一份
...to include it on The List of Avignon, of which, by the way, we hold a copy.
这些东西真棒
Perfect job for these babies.
我自己做的
Made them myself.
有圣水 丁香叶 银屑 白橡木 这肯定有效
Holy water, clove leaf, silver shavings, white oak. The works.
这扇门后面 有一个黑暗的怪物
Behind this door, a dark entity.
凶狠 古老 而且饥饿
Evil, ancient and hungry.
哦 好啊 让我进去和它打个招呼吧
Oh, well. Let me go in and say hi.
你最好查查资料 蓝鱼兄弟
You better hit the books, Brother Blue.
我们肯定需要关于这家伙的更多信息
We'll definitely need more info on this one.
没人和他一起去? 天啊
Hey, no one goes with him? Jesus.
不 他喜欢这样
No. He likes it that way.
孤胆英雄嘛
The whole ''lonely hero'' thing.
粘鬼
Hey, Stinky.
厨房已经打烊了
Kitchen's closed.
你都吃了点什么?
What you having?
生吃了六个图书馆警卫 还有腰带和靴子
Six library guards, raw, plus belts and boots.
老兄 你得多吃点素的才能消化掉
Man, you're gonna need some heavy fiber to move that out.
红大个 我发现了些东西
Red, I found something.
这已经绝迹的怪物叫萨莫艾尔
This entity's name is Sammael, the desolate one.
尼尔加之子
Son of Nergal, brother of...
我说 萨莫
Listen, Sammy...
我枪法不怎么准 不过这枪的子弹可不小
...l'm not a very good shot, but The Samaritan here uses really big bullets.
那么我们来个漂亮和平的方式如何
So, what do you say we work this out in a nice, peaceful....
他妈的
Oh, crap.
萨莫 不听话就这种下场
That's it for you, Sam.
红大个 你应该听听其余的信息
Red, you need to hear the rest of the information.
不用了 他被解决了
No, he's taken care of.
不 听听这个
No, listen to this.
萨莫艾尔 已绝迹的种类 黑暗的领主...
''Sammael, the desolate one, lord of the shadows...
尼尔加之子 能够重生...
...son of Nergal, hound of resurrection.... ''
我说
See...
我可不喜欢这样
...l don't like that.
不喜欢什么? 能够重生?
What? Hound of resurrection?
"瘟疫的前兆 毁灭的萌芽"
''Harbinger of pestilence. Seed of destruc...''
直接说关键部分吧 我怎么杀掉它?
Cut to the end. How do l kill it?
这上面没说
Doesn't say.
到前面去 冲啊!
Go to the front. Let's go! Move!
我绕到后面去
l'm going around the back.
糟糕
Oh, crap.
孩子
Child.
都长大了啊
All grown up, l see.
那声音
That voice.
那是你听过的第一首催眠曲 我的孩子
lt was the first lullaby you ever heard, my son.
我引领你来到这个世界
l ushered you into this world.
只有我知道你的真名
l alone know your true calling, your true name.
是嘛 那这个叫什么
Name this.
- 那东西 那东西 - 你认为你在干什么?
- That thing. That thing. - What do you think you're doing?
- 你认为你在干什么? - 帮你啊 我...
- What do you think you're doing? - Helping you. l...
没人能帮我!
Nobody helps me!
这就是我的工作!
lt's my job.
你想帮忙吗 这里 帮我上子弹
You want to help? Here. Load this.
这是跟踪弹 把弹头弄破
lt's a tracking bullet. Crack the pin.
天啊 你胳膊上是什么?
Jesus, what's that on your arm?
他妈的
Oh, crap.
那东西到底是什么?
What the hell is that thing?
让我去问问它
Let me go ask.
好的 继续前进 不错 继续
All right, keep coming. Good. Keep coming.
干嘛 你这个小...
Why, you little....
等一下
Wait!
我们正冲向平民
We're heading toward civilians.
很漂亮的化妆对吧? 不给糖果就捣蛋
Crazy costumes, huh? Trick or treat.
红灯就意味着停车!
Red means stop!
- 你还好吧? - 是的
- You all right? - Yeah.
待在这里
Stay here.
萨莫 你有伤口了
Sammy, you got a leak.
在等我吗 大脸怪?
Waiting for me, chunk-face?
什么?
What the...
- 我和你都是一个头的 - 没错
- l'm on your side. - Sure.
干得漂亮!
That's right!
张开!
Open wide!
娘的
Son of a...
恶心!
Yuck!
尝尝这个吧
Screw this.
我不怕火的
l'm fireproof.
而你怕
You're not.
迈尔斯
Hey, Myers.
我在 我在
Yeah? Yeah? Yeah?
你胳膊怎么样了?
How's your arm?
我胳膊没事 你在哪里?
Yeah, my arm's fine. Where are you?
我刚刚把粘鬼炸了
l just fried Stinky.
听着
Listen...
告诉老爸我会回家的
...tell Father l'll be home...
不过让他别等我
...but he shouldn't wait up.
别别 等一下
No. No, wait, wait.
我得和你一起去
Yeah, I gotta go with you.
- 迈尔斯 - 什么?
- Hey, Myers. - Yeah?
再见
Bye.
妈的
Damn it.
(废弃地下铁衣帽间)
萨莫艾尔完成了他的使命
Sammael has fulfilled his destiny.
愿他安息
Die in peace...
等待下一次的重生
...and be reborn again and again.
离月蚀还剩七天了
Only seven more days till the eclipse.
那孩子会到那里去 我们也会去的
The child will be there, and so will we all.
不是吗?
Won't we?
(贝尔拉米精神病医院 轻症监护组)
那有个大个子的红人在那里
There's a big, red man down there.
亲爱的 没事 圣诞老人还要一个月才能来呢
That's fine, darling. Santa's not here for another month.
不是圣诞老人
Not Santa.
那是谁?
Well, who, then?
我带啤酒来了
l brought beer.
哦 红大个 你的胳膊
Oh, Red, your arm.
你最好找医生看看
You better get that looked at.
我想见你
l wanted to see you.
每一次媒体见到他 就跑来找我
Every time the media gets a look at him, they run to me.
我已经没有谎话可说了 特瑞沃尔
l'm running out of lies, Trevor.
- 我还以为你喜欢上电视呢 - 我是喜欢
- l thought you like being on TV. - l do.
不过今年他已经逃跑五回了!
So how many escapes this year alone? Five.
汤姆 他是我们的客人 不是囚犯
Tom, he's our guest, not a prisoner.
你的客人可是有六英尺五英寸高
Your guest is
亮红色皮肤 长尾巴 而且由政府供养
has a tail and is government-funded.
我知道去哪里找他
l know where to find him.
- 我会把他弄回来的 - 鱼叉
- l'll get him back. - Hey, fish stick.
别碰任何东西
Don't touch anything.
我必须碰才能看见
l need to touch it to see.
- 看见什么? - 过去 未来
- See what? - Past, future.
任何和这个东西有关的事情
Whatever this object holds.
他是说真的吗?
ls he serious?
别担心指纹 我从来没有指纹
Don't worry about fingerprints. Never had any.
教授 他们来过
Professor, they were here.
谁来过? 尼克松? 胡迪尼?
Who was here? Nixon? Houdini?
吉米·胡佛? 谁啊?
Jimmy Hoffa? Who?
让我看看 艾比 让我看看这里发生的事情
Show me, Abe. Show me what happened here.
我们是东翼检查组 一切正常
This is east-wing check-in. We're all clear.
另外 记住把副馆的展品都锁起来
Also, make sure it's all locked up over there in the annex.
明白
Roger that.
克鲁南!
Kroenen!
让开
Move.
让开!
Move!
他在那
There he is!
我们从这里掩护他!
We'll cover him from here!
好啦 不要动 放下那东西
All right, don't move! Put that down.
把武器放下!
Put down the weapon!
你去对付他们
Get them.
放下武器
Drop the weapon.
趴在地上!
On the ground!
最后警告!
Last warning!
干掉他!
Take him out!
现在 准备欢迎它吧 亲爱的
Now, ready the welcome, my love.
数千个天使的眼泪凝结的盐粒
Salt gathered from the tears of a thousand angels.
封印了地狱犬
Restraining the essence...
萨莫艾尔的灵魂
...of Sammael, the hellhound.
毁灭的萌芽
The seed of destruction.
这次我可以向你保证 萨莫艾尔
This l can promise, Sammael.
每一个你倒下去
For each one of you that falls...
两个新的你就会重生
...two shall arise.
- 教授 - 我很好
- Professor. - l'm all right.
教授
Professor.
你...
You....
你看起来病得很重
You are very sick.
我不希望地狱男爵知道
l don't want Hellboy to know.
六十年前 他们试图毁灭世界
Sixty years ago, they tried to destroy the world.
现在他们又回来了
They're back.
在我的残生中 他们又回来了...
ln my lifetime, they're back...
完成他们未尽的使命
...to finish the job.
我们在局里很怀念你
We miss you at the bureau.
艾比每天都更疯狂
Abe's crazier every day.
老爸还是对我发脾气
Father's still mad at me.
回来吧 丽兹
Come back, Liz.
- 回来吧 - 不 不行 地狱男爵
- Come back. - No. No, H.B.
不行 现在不行
No, not this time.
我也不喜欢这里
l don't like it here...
但我已经几个月没有幻觉了
...but l haven't had an episode in months.
你知道吗
And you know what?
我开始能控制它了
l'm learning to control it.
我知道它的来源
l'm learning where it comes from.
这是我生命中第一次
For the first time in my life...
不再感到害怕了
...l'm not afraid.
- 看来接你的车已经来了 - 让护送人员待命
- Looks like your ride is here. - Have escort stand by.
保姆小队
The Nanny Squad.
嗨 站住 等一下
Hey, stop. Wait. Wait.
长官 能让我先进去吗?
Sir, may l go first?
等一等
Hang on a minute.
地狱男爵对他还不熟
He barely knows him.
那就让他自己来改变这点吧
Then he should make it his business to change that.
听着 地狱男爵
Listen, H.B...
我在这里还有希望
...l've got a chance out here.
如果你真的关心我
So if you really care about me...
就不要再来了
...you won't come back.
好吧
Yeah...
我也得走了
...l gotta go too.
还有很多事要做
Lots to do.
怎么你这么久才进来?
What took you so long?
来吧 该回家了
Come on, time to go home.
帮你包扎伤口
Tape you up.
你是什么 多愁善感的童子军吗?
What are you, a Boy Scout?
- 不 我从未当过 - 好吧 你可能骗过了我
- Nope, l never was. - Well, you could have fooled me.
红大个
Hey, Red.
天啊 你流了好多血
Oh, God. You've lost a lot of blood.
这没什么
This is nothing.
你该知道是什么能让我真正受伤 对吧?
You know what'll kill me, don't you?
好啦 红大个 让我们带你回去吧 来吧
Okay, Red, let's get you home. Come on.
你被一些有机酸烧伤
You were burned by some organic acid.
我够走运的了
l'm lucky that way.
- 我很担心你 - 担心我?
- l worry about you. - Me?
这个...
Well...
...我不会永远活着 你知道的
...l won't be around forever, you know.
该死!
Damn!
你就不能小心点吗?
Could you please be a little careful?
好的 大块头
Big baby.
它抓住你有多长时间?
How long was it latched onto you?
不太清楚 大概五秒钟
l don't know. About five seconds.
- 教授 看 - 严重吗
- Professor, look. - ls it bad?
抓住你五秒钟 就下了三个蛋
Touched you five seconds, laid three eggs.
也不给我买杯饮料
Didn't even buy me a drink.
刺鳌从舌头上分离 把蛋注入
The stinger detaches itself from the tongue and injects the eggs.
它们对于光线和温度极其敏感
They are very sensitive to heat and light.
它们需要潮湿黑暗的环境生长
They need a humid, dark environment to breed.
你有没有没让他离开过你的视线?
Did you ever lose track of him?
这个 让我想想
Well, let's see.
当火车从我头上开过去的时候 我没有看住他
There was that moment when l had the train on top of my head.
我们不能冒险
We can't risk it.
明天你和一组探员回到铁轨那里
Tomorrow you'll go back to the tracks with a group of agents.
把整个地区彻底搜索一遍
Search the whole place top to bottom.
找到那些蛋 除掉它们
Find those eggs and destroy them.
"伊丽莎白·谢尔曼"
''Elizabeth Sherman.''
我不喜欢"点火器"这个称呼
I don't like the term ''fire-starter. ''
我就是不喜欢
I just don't.
而"火焰风暴"听起来又好像精神错乱什么的
And "pyrokinesis" sounds like some psychosis or something.
我不知道
I don't know.
也许那是对的吧
Maybe that's right.
不能对这点释怀
Not being able to let go.
真可怕
It's scary.
每一次幻觉后我都会昏过去 有时数小时之久
I black out after each episode. Sometimes for hours.
你听说过很多...
You hear about so and so...
人们无法自控而歇斯底里的事
...who just lost control and just exploded.
他们很走运 因为那不是真的
Well, they're lucky it isn't true.
但对我来说却是真实的
With me, it is.
我的主人在呼唤你的名字 我的女孩
My master is calling your name now, my girl.
你必须回到小孩的形态
You must return to the child.
所以再一次...
So once again...
梦见...
...dream...
圣火
...of fire.
怪胎!
Hey, freak!
回到这里来 怪胎!
Get back here, freak!
- 我们去捉弄她! - 捉弄她!
- Let's get her! - Get her!
- 伙计们 捉弄她! - 看这个!
- Get her, guys! - Watch this!
怪胎!
Freak!
不要! 不要再来了
Oh, no! Not again.
不要! 来人啊!
Oh, no! Somebody!
救救我!
Help me!
救救我! 来人啊! 救救我!
Help me, somebody! Help me!
她还得烧掉多少座建筑?
How many buildings does she have to burn down?
她属于这儿
She belongs here.
她不这么觉得
That's not what she feels.
她可能永远不会回来了 这是她的选择
She may never feel it. lt's her choice.
教授 那女孩...
Professor, the girl you're...
教授 你正谈及的那女孩...
Professor, that girl you're talking about....
侦察员小子
Hey, Boy Scout...
童子军
想好再说
...think twice.
不 听着 我读了她的档案
No, listen, l read her file.
- "读了她的档案" - 她在自责
- ''Read her file.'' - She blames herself...
为了那场美国匹兹堡的那场爆炸
...for that explosion in Pittsburgh.
我想我能帮上忙
Look, I think I can help.
我可以去和她谈谈
l could talk to her.
我想我能把她带回来
l think l could bring her back.
是什么让你得到这个送"煎饼"的工作?
Just what was it that landed you this job pushing ''pamcakes,'' huh?
是什么?
What was it?
是你的守时? 还是你摆弄发型的方式?
Punctuality? The way you part your hair?
你的专业领域是什么?
What is your area of expertise?
他不想我和他在一起
He doesn't want me with him.
我知道
l know that much.
- 你做得很好 - 不 我没有
- You're doing fine. - No, l'm not.
他尊敬的是克里 不是我
Look, he respects Clay, not me.
我很抱歉 行了吧?
l'm really sorry, okay?
我不是你要的人
l'm not your guy.
我快死了 迈尔斯探员
l'm dying, Agent Myers.
像其他父亲一样 我很担心他
Like any father, l worry about him.
在中世纪传奇故事里都会有一位年轻的骑士
ln medieval stories, there is often a young knight...
他没有多少经验
...who is inexperienced...
- 但却有着纯真的心 - 拜托
- ...but pure of heart. - Come on.
我并没有什么纯真的心
Look, l am not pure of heart.
不 你有
Yes, you are.
拉斯普亭回来找他了
Rasputin is back for him.
我唯一要你做的就是
What l ask of you...
在我离去后在他身边勇敢地支持他
...is to have the courage to stand by him when l am gone.
他天生就是恶魔 这无法改变
He was born a demon. Can't change that.
但你能帮助他
But you will help him...
从本质上
...in essence...
成为一个男人
...to become a man.
把那个拉下来
Pull that down.
她本来复原得很好
She was making great progress...
现在却发生了这事故
...and now this.
我们会关门数月
We'll be closed for months.
这造成我们氯丙嗪药剂供应的短缺
And it put a big dent in our Thorazine supply.
事故发生后 她就一直这个样子
She's been like this since it happened.
你确定你想进去吗?
Are you sure you want to go in?
谢尔曼女士?
Miss Sherman?
我是联邦调查局的迈尔斯探员
l'm Agent Myers, FBl.
谢尔曼女士?
Miss Sherman?
我能叫你丽兹吗?
Can l call you Liz?
美丽的名字
lt's a beautiful name.
全世界百分之六十的女性都叫丽兹
Sixty percent of all the women in the world are named Liz.
对 但我个人非常喜欢这个名字 我叫约翰
Well, it's impressive by my standards. My name's John.
约翰·T·迈尔斯
John T. Myers.
布隆姆博士要我邀请你重回部门
Dr. Broom asked me to invite you back to the bureau.
没有特殊的预防措施 没有安全人员的护送
No special precautions, no security escorts.
就像普通人 你和我坐出租车回去
Just you and me in a taxi like regular folks.
那不像是他说的话
That doesn't sound like him.
谢尔曼女士 他在请求你回去
Well, Miss Sherman, he's asking you back...
但你可以做出自己的选择 知道吗?
...but it's entirely your choice, you know?
选择?
Choice, huh?
那中听
That's cute.
我已经离开过这部门十三次了
l've quit the bureau 13 times.
我每次又总是回去
l always go back.
我还有其它什么地方可去的?
Where else would l go?
"废弃的地铁空地"在这里
Over here.
你说过那些蛋需要黑暗潮湿的环境
You said those eggs need it dark and humid?
它们这回可中大奖了
Well, they hit the jackpot.
在地铁线 它们全集中在这里
The subway lines, they all converge right around here.
在我们正下方 有座古老的凡迪维尔水库
Right below us is the old Vandeveer reservoir.
水库在30年代中期就被废弃了
lt was abandoned in the mid-30s.
有脉冲信号
There's a pulse.
那里 在另一边有个蓄水池
There. A cistern on the other side.
大多数蛋都在那里
Most of the eggs are there.
没有路进去
There's no way in.
我们应该回去申请特别的二号类型许可
We should go back and request a special permit, type 2...
你们来还是不来?
You guys coming or what?
我们会带你过一种无害的生活
We lead a charmed life.
这里 医生
Here you are, doctor.
这个应能保护你
This should cover your tail fin.
罗马教廷的圣骨匣
Reliquary. Straight from the Vatican.
圣徒狄奥尼修斯的骨头 看起来像小手指
A bone from St. Dionysius. Looks like a pinkie.
告诉我为什么是我去做?
Remind me why l keep doing this.
腐臭的蛋和全人类的安全
Rotten eggs and the safety of mankind.
看上去并不像洋娃娃的头发
This doesn't really look like doll's hair.
说实话 红大个 你认为呢?
Be honest, Red. What do you think?
我在想我来帮你梳理得了
l'm thinking about doing it myself.
你们有什么发现?
Hey, you guys find anything?
还没发现蛋 红大个
No eggs yet, Red.
什么 你在午餐休息吗?
What, are you on a lunch break?
这里没有
Nothing here.
红大个正在行动 我会掩护他
Red's on the move. l'll cover him.
见鬼 红大个
Damn it, Red.
是艾比
Hey, it's Abe.
上帝
Oh, God.
把你的武器拿过来
Bring your toy over here.
天哪
Oh, man.
天啊
Oh, Jesus.
只有一个 我会很快煎熟它
There's only one. l'll fry him quick.
两个 有两个
Two. There were two.
红大个?
Red?
红大个 回话 红大个
Red. Come in, Red.
你在哪里? 我接受不到信号 你到底在哪里?
What's your 20? l got no signal. Where the hell are you?
这里的地形像瑞士硬干酪
It's like Swiss cheese in here.
伙计 悠着点 我在追他
Sit tight, pal, l'm on him.
萨莫艾尔 可以重生的地狱之犬
Sammael, hound of the resurrection.
我不是已杀了你吗?
Didn't l kill you already?
你这讨厌的怪物!
You goddamn monster!
糟糕
Oh, crap.
这是你的电话!
lt's for you!
你不应该伤害人!
You shouldn't hurt people!
你没打中
You missed.
大脸怪
Hey, chunk-face.
像你这样的大怪物 应该攻击得更好才是
You can do better than that, big monster like you.
请救救我的小猫!
My kittens! Please!
来人啊 请救救我的小猫!
Somebody, please, get my kittens!
才第二次约会
Second date.
不要用舌头
No tongue.
小心我的小猫!
My kittens. Careful with them!
女士 不要烦我!
Lady, give me a break!
谢谢你
Thank you.
这是我的工作
My job.
克里 我接受到艾比的信号 我正赶回来
Clay, I'm getting a signal from Abe. I'm on my way back.
伙计 不要再上前了
Buddy, don't take another step.
克里...
Clay.
有人员伤亡 需要一辆救护车 立刻派来 收到了吗?
Man down. l need an ambulance right away. Do you read me?
兄弟 坚持住
Hang in there, pal.
有人员伤亡 收到了吗 收到了吗
Man down. Do you read? Do you read?
科瑞尔 莫斯 收到了吗
Quarry, Moss, do you read me?
科瑞尔 莫斯 收到了吗 有人员伤亡
Quarry, Moss, do you read me? Man down!
外面的感觉真好 好久都没这样了
Feels good to be outside. lt's been so long.
那样不安全 谢尔曼女士
You know that's... That's not safe Miss Sherman.
请待在车里
Please stay in the car.
谢尔曼女士 请不要这样 你能坐下来吗?
No, no. Miss Sherman. Please, can you come down, Miss Sherman?
风景真好
Nice view.
笑一笑 那就对了
Hey, a smile, huh? Yeah, that's good.
给你
Here.
见鬼
Damn.
- 等会你得再给我照一张 - 好的
- You'll have to take another one later. - Yeah.
他会好起来的
He'll make it.
但不是每个人都这么幸运
Not everyone was so lucky.
两位探员殉职了
We had two agents die today.
克里也许活不过今晚
Clay probably won't survive the night.
- 曼宁 现在请别提这些 - 我想你的问题是...
- Not now, Manning, please. - My problem with you:
你做事不顾后果
You're reckless.
那些人信任你 让你做团队的头儿
These men trusted you to lead them as a team.
你去哪儿呢?
Where were you?
我比你更了解这些人
l knew those men better than you did.
- 那么 你就安心了 - 不 这并不使我安心
- That makes it all right, then. - No, it doesn't make it all right.
- 但我至少制服了那玩意儿 是吧? - 是的 你制服了
- But l stopped that thing, didn't l? - Yes, you did.
这就是你的工作 这就是为什么我们需要你
lt's what you do. lt's why we need you.
你有一种洞察力 你了解这些怪物
You have an insight. You know monsters.
你到底想说什么?
What are you trying to say?
这整件事是一场闹剧
This whole thing is a farce.
因为到最后...
Because in the end...
...在你杀光 捉光了所有的怪物后...
...after you've killed, after you've captured every freak out there...
...还是有个剩下的怪物
...there's still one left.
就是你
You.
曼宁
Hey, Manning.
我希望我能更友好一些 但...
l wish l could be more gracious, but....
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
布隆姆教授 我只在这里待一个周末
lt's only for the weekend, Professor Broom.
然后我就该走了
Then l shall be on my way.
你应该四处看看
Oh, you should have a look around.
这里变化不小
We made some changes around here.
我要把这个东西关起来 马上就关
l want that thing locked up, starting now.
马上就关! 你听到...
Right now! Do you...
现在就关 你听到了吗?
Now, you hear me?
- 把他关起来! - 他一点也没改变
- Locked up! - Nothing's changed.
家 甜蜜的家
Home sweet home.
丽兹?
Liz?
丽兹!
Liz!
你把她带来了 兄弟 你把她带来了!
You did it, buddy. You did it!
迈尔斯?
Myers?
老爸?
Pop?
你还好吗
Hey, how you doing?
你手腕上是什么东西?
Hey, what's that on your wrist?
这个吗
This?
- 这是我从心理治疗中学来的 - 嗯?
- lt's something l learned in therapy. - Yeah?
我感到沮丧 就拉一次橡皮圈
l'm depressed, one rubber band.
感到焦虑
l'm impatient...
拉两次橡皮圈
...two rubber bands.
也许...
Maybe....
我该捆紧你的一个橡皮圈
Maybe l should get you a fresh pack.
嗯 也许两个
Yeah, maybe two.
是啊 也许吧
Yeah, maybe.
我把这些食物放在这里 好吗?
l'm gonna put these over here, okay?
等一等 等一等
One minute. One minute.
嗨 迈尔斯...
Hey, Myers...
...你是一个善于言辞的人
...you're a talker.
就表达"需要"来说 有没有更好的词语?
What's a good word, a solid word, for ''need''?
这个...
Well...
..."需要"本身就是很好的词
...''need'' is a good, solid word.
太直白了
Too needy.
开始吃吧? 还有墨西哥烤玉米片要送来
Start in, okay? You got nachos coming.
墨西哥烤玉米片
Nachos.
我的上帝
Oh, my God.
看看这整堆垃圾
Look at them all.
谁养了小孩吗?
Who had babies?
丽兹 有些事你得听我说说 这...
Liz, there's something l need for you to hear, and it's....
时间长吗?因为我马上要出去了
Will it take long? Because l'm actually going out.
出去?
Out?
是"离开" 还是去散心?
''Out'' out?
出去喝杯咖啡 但你继续 读吧
Yeah. Yeah, for a cup of coffee, but go ahead, read.
你一个人去?
Are you going alone?
不 迈尔斯带我出去
No, Myers is taking me.
你的红辣椒酱快冷了
Hey, your chili's getting cold.
我不饿
Not hungry.
你不是要跟我说些事吗?
ls there something you'd like me to hear?
- 这是一个列表 但还未完成 - 好的
- lt's just a list. lt's not finished. - Okay.
好 那么 迟点再说吧
Well, then, later.
回头见
See you.
- 你还需要什么? - 不用你管
- Anything else you need? - Not from you.
那好 晚安
Well, good night.
再见
Goodbye.
研究对象 卡尔·卢布里切特·克鲁南
Subject: Karl Ruprecht Kroenen.
1897年生于德国慕尼黑
Born in Munich, 1897.
患上一种叫"外科手术嗜爱狂"
Suffered from a masochistic compulsion...
...的虐待狂强迫症
...commonly known as surgical addiction.
眼皮都被移除了...
Both eyelids surgically removed...
...上嘴唇...
...along with his upper...
...和下嘴唇也一样
...and lower lip.
血管中的血液早已干涸
The blood in his veins dried up decades ago.
只剩尘土
Only dust remains.
什么样的恐怖意志...
What horrible will...
...能使这样的生物还活着?
...could keep such a creature as this alive?
不
Oh, no.
来吧 红大个
Come on, Red.
天啊
Jesus.
该死 红大个 别再逃了
Damn it, Red. Not again
来份那种甜饼 你这儿有油炸圈饼吗
And one of those cookies. Do you have any doughnuts?
对不起 朋友 来个"熊爪"怎么样?
Sorry, pal. How about a bear claw?
还想要些什么吗? 店快打烊了
Do you want anything else? The shop's closing.
我们走吧
Here we go.
听着...
Listen about....
我钦佩他 他是自然之力
l admire him. He's a force of nature.
你俩出来要谈些什么?
What are you two talking about?
什么事会如此的迷人和重要?
What is so fascinating, so important?
不 他太顽固而且不听劝告
No. He's determined, unstoppable.
有人会把那看作自以为是
Some people would call that cocky.
- 他只是太好强了 - 是啊 他就是这样
- He's just strong. - Yeah. That he is.
我拿了你的那份
Hey, l've got yours.
我叔叔 他以前常说 我们喜欢人是因为他们的优点...
My uncle, he used to say we like people for their qualities...
...但爱上人却是因为他们的缺点
...but love them for their defects.
他爱你 你知道的
He loves you, you know.
你对他呢?
What about you?
我说不清 我和他是青梅竹马
l don't know. l grew up with him.
但现在每当我一看到他 我就感到困扰
But now every time l see him, l get confused.
几乎每天他都在我的脑海里
There's hardly a day that goes by that he's not in my mind.
甚至现在...
Even now...
...我都感觉好像他在这里
...l feel like he's here.
等等我
Hey, wait up.
你爱吃油炸圈饼吗 我有两个
You like doughnuts? l got two.
- 谢谢 很好吃 - 我还有个甜饼
- Thanks. That was nice. - l got a cookie, as well.
- 要糖吗? - 谢谢你 不要糖
- Sugar? - No. No sugar. Thank you.
笨蛋 不要给她奶油和糖 她喜欢喝黑咖啡
No cream and sugar, moron. She takes it black.
- 我这里有些牛奶 - 不用 我不喝牛奶
- l got some milk here. - No. l'm okay. l don't take milk.
我说对了吧
Told you.
她为他照相
She took his picture.
该死!
Damn!
她为他照相
She took his picture.
糟糕
Oh, crap.
真冷啊 是吧?
lt's freezing, isn't it?
喝咖啡使我感到暖和
Coffee's warming me up.
那现在我们去干什么?
Well, what do we do now?
新泽西州的纽沃克 娱乐首府
Newark, New Jersey, entertainment capital of the world.
- 你听上去像个游戏节目的主持人 - 你好
- You sound like a game-show host. - Hi.
你是地狱男爵
You're Hellboy.
我在执行任务
l'm on a mission.
说说你的一些事 你从哪里来?
All right, tell me something about you. Where do you come from?
我以前大部分时间和我叔叔一起生活
l lived with my uncle most of my life.
后来我去了弗吉尼亚州的匡提柯 当上了我班上的头名
Then l went to Quantico, went to top of my class.
我一点也不像...
I'm nothing like...
不要告诉别人见过我好吗
Don't tell anyone, huh?
好小子
Attaboy.
长官 他没有带上定位器
Sir, he left his locator.
- 我们该派人去找他吗 - 够了 受够了
- Shall we send out some scouts? - Enough, enough, enough.
他永远也长不大
He'll never change.
小孩子
A child.
永远都是小孩子
Always a child.
塞巴斯蒂安公墓 第十六号
Sebastian Plackba, number 16.
在莫斯科
Moscow.
是什么人想对付我们?
Who wants us in Moscow?
- 我老妈烤的饼干 - 她在笑
- My mom baked them. - She's laughing.
她坐在公园的长椅子上 而且她在大笑
She's sitting on a park bench, and she's laughing.
就这样了 我完了
That's it. l'm done.
他们看上去不像是间谍
They don't look like spies.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
看看那个家伙
Look at this guy.
那阴险的小眼 那咧嘴的假笑
Those shady little eyes, that phony grin.
- 你会吃那个吗 - 不
- Are you going to eat that? - No.
他在打哈欠 他感到无聊
Hey, he's yawning. He's bored.
老土的打哈欠花招
Yeah, the old yawning trick.
看着他的手臂
Watch his arm.
首先他想要我的工作 接着他想要我的女友
First he wants my job, then he wants my girl.
我们每人都有自己尽力隐藏的另一面
Hey, we all have a side that we try to hide.
天啊...
God...
怎么回事?
Hey, what the hell?
谁扔的?
Hey! Hey, who threw that?
- 你没事吧? - 还好
- Are you okay? - Yeah, l'm fine.
扔得真准
Nice shot.
塞巴斯蒂安公墓 第十六号
Sebastian Plackba, number 16.
那是拉斯普亭的陵墓
lt's Rasputin's mausoleum.
我看见了木偶
l see the puppet.
但那操纵木偶的人...
But where is...
...在哪里?
...the puppeteer?
很好 布隆姆教授
Very good, Professor Broom.
是你
lt was you.
那纸的碎片...
The scraps of paper...
...丽兹突然爆发和回归
...Liz's sudden relapse and return.
就像在寓言中
Bread crumbs on the trail.
用面包屑来标记道路
Like in a fable.
这些事转移了他的注意力...
They both distract him...
...并指引他到我要他去的地方
...and guide him exactly where l need him.
莫斯科
Moscow.
他的宿命之地
His destiny.
而最后的一个线索...
And the last clue...
...将是已故的布隆姆教授
...will be left by the late Professor Broom.
你养大了这孩子
You raised the child.
教育了他
Nurtured him.
所以作为回报...
So in return...
...我允许你...
...l will permit you...
...看一眼未来的情形
...a brief, brief glimpse of the future.
他将打开地狱之门...
He will open the portal...
...带来世界的末日
...and bring about the end of the world.
如果六十年前你杀掉他...
If only you had had him destroyed 60 years ago...
...那这一切就不会发生
...none of this would have come to pass.
但你又怎么可能知道呢?
But then, how could you have known?
你的上帝选择了沉默
Your God chooses to remain silent.
而我的却与我同在
Mine lives within me.
每次当我死掉并重生后...
Every time l died and crossed over...
...就会带回...
...a little more of the master...
...主人的一小部分
...came back with me.
他向我展示了孩子的真名
He disclosed to me the child's true name.
你想知道吗
Would you like to know it?
我知道他的名字
l know what to call him.
无论你说或者做什么
Nothing you can do or say...
都无法改变
...can change that.
我叫他...
l call him...
...儿子
...Son.
我准备好了
l'm ready.
会很快的
lt'll be quick.
直接过去告诉她你的感受
Just go there and tell her how you feel.
我老妈常说...
My mom says that...
瞧 这没有那么简单 明白吗
Look, it's not... lt's not that easy, okay?
而且 你才九岁
Plus, you're 9.
你还没有老到可以给我建议
You're not old enough to be giving me advice.
- 好的 停下来 - 那些人是谁?
- All right, stand by. - Who are those guys?
丽兹 对不起 是布隆姆出事了 我们走吧 我们得找到他
Liz, l'm sorry. lt's Broom. Let's go. We need to find him.
- 不! - 等等 发生了什么?
- No! - Wait, what happened?
- 不会的! - 没事的
- No! - lt's okay.
不要 不会是他
No, not him.
- 你能带她回去吗 - 不对劲
- Would you take her? - Something's wrong.
他已经三天没和任何人说过话了
He hasn't spoken to anybody in three days.
一句也没有
Not a word.
他既不吃也不睡
He won't eat, he won't sleep.
我从没见过他这样
l've never seen him like this.
从来没有
Never.
我该留下吗
Should l stay?
留下来陪他
With him, l mean?
听着 我并不是一个问题解决专家
Listen, l'm not much of a problem solver.
三十年来 我只完成了魔方的两面
Three decades, l've only completed two sides.
但我知道这一点
But l do know this much.
如果有麻烦的话...
lf there's trouble...
...我们这些怪胎只能相互信任
...all us freaks have is each other.
我被困在这里
And l'm stuck here.
所以...
So...
可以为我照顾好那大猴子吗
...take care of the big monkey for me, will you?
(莫斯科 陀波科巴军事基地)
我收藏了很多有趣的事物...
l have accumulated many objects of great interest...
以保存我们的文化传统
...preserving our heritage.
很多人 和我一样 都相信祖国母亲...
Many, like me, believe Mother Russia...
即将迎来一个历史性的重生
...to be very close to a historic rebirth.
重生?
''Rebirth''?
我喜欢那词
l like that.
二十吨重的岩石
Twenty tons of stone.
这是坠落到通古斯森林中的那块陨石
This thing fell from the sky into Tunguska Forest.
1908年6月30日
June 30th, 1908.
当时的罗曼诺夫王朝立刻占有了它
The Romanovs took possession of it immediately.
我早就想得到它了
l've wanted it for ages.
你应该知道...
You're aware, of course...
你无法把它带出俄罗斯领土
...there's no way you'll get it out of Russian territory.
他知道的 我们的客人会来俄罗斯
He is aware. Our guests are coming in.
维罗克拉斯基郊外 距离莫斯科50英里 那是我们的目的地
Volokolamsk Fields, 50 miles from Moscow, that's where we're going.
塞巴斯蒂安公墓 第十六号 这是我们唯一的线索
Sebastian Plackba, number 16. That's the only clue we have.
我们已经收集并毁灭了数以千计的蛋...
We've collected and destroyed thousands of eggs...
但我们仍没有萨莫艾尔或拉斯普亭的踪迹
...but we have no trace of this Sammael or this Rasputin character.
我们一得到许可和装备就行动
We leave as soon as we get clearance and equipment.
地狱男爵会一起来
Hellboy's coming.
我对此感到不愉快 但这次我是负责人
l'm not pleased about that, but l'll be in charge this time.
我们这次得隐秘行动 不然这怪物就别想再出来了
We either wrap this up or l'm closing this freak show for good.
我会...
l'll...
...去莫斯科...
...come to Moscow...
...如果你还去的话
...if you're still going.
我会去
l am.
但我有些话想说
But l have something to say.
我理解你不喜欢我的原因
l understand what you don't like about me.
我理解
l do.
我是恶魔...
What l am...
...这使你感到有些不适...
...makes you feel a little out of place...
...想离开这里
...out there.
- 红大个 我没有... - 听好
- Red, l don't... - Listen.
我不像迈尔斯
l'm not like Myers.
你觉得他才是你的归属
He makes you feel like you belong...
...那真的很好
...which is good, really.
我希望可以改变自己的容貌
l wish l could do something about this.
但我无法做到
l can't.
我向你保证两件事
l can promise you two things:
第一 我会永远是这样
One, l'll always look this good.
第二
And two...
我决不放弃爱你
...l'll never give up on you.
决不会
Ever.
我喜欢那样
l like that.
(俄罗斯领空)
这上面刻的是萨莫艾尔 铭文写道
This engraving here represents Sammy. Text reads:
死一个会有两个重生
''One falls, two shall arise. Sammael.''
我们必须得同时把它们和蛋干掉
We'll have to nail them all at once, and the eggs.
行动时不要恣意妄为
And when we do, no mumbo jumbo.
双核Vulcan65型手雷
Double-core Vulcan-65 grenades.
上面已装好定时器 设置好就离开
We've installed a handy little timer. You set it, you walk away.
线会拉开安全别针
Cable pulls the safety pins.
轰隆
Kaboom.
容易清理容易使用
Easy to clean, easy to use.
(莫斯科 维罗克拉斯基郊外)
火花对红大个讲话 听到吗请回话
Sparky to Big Red. Do you read me? Come in.
火花?
''Sparky''?
谁想出来的? 迈尔斯吗
Who came up with that? Myers?
是的 我们现在要离开主车道 抓紧
Yeah, we're leaving the main road, so hang on.
这最好就是那地方 我快要晕车呕吐了
This better be the place or l'll puke.
你最好出来看看
You better come out and see.
塞巴斯蒂安公墓 第十六号
Sebastian Plackba, number 16.
算了 我们永远无法找到那陵墓
Forget it. We're never gonna find Rasputin's mausoleum.
这简直就是一座城
lt's practically a city.
又臭又脏
And it stinks, and it's muddy.
我建议先回去找个旅馆 整顿好
l think we go back, we check into the hotel, we regroup.
吃完早饭后再来
After breakfast.
我们要做的就是建立起一个方格图
l think what we have to do here is we have to make a grid.
我们按图的象限进行搜寻 也许用卫星照片
We go in by quadrants. Maybe satellite photography.
让我来问路
Let me ask for directions.
你去哪儿?
Where are you going?
来吧 宝贝 帮我找一个会说话的
Come on, baby, find me a talker.
你好
Hi there.
来吧
Come on.
你想要什么?
这太荒谬了
This is ridiculous.
主管是我 不是他
l run this show, not him.
这家伙只会惹麻烦
This guy's nothing but trouble.
- 过去十分钟了 我们走吧 - 你能不能闭嘴
- Ten minutes, we're out of here. - Will you shut up...
就让他这样去做
...and let him do his thing?
有人还有能量棒吗
Anybody got a PowerBar?
他回来了
Hey, there he is.
再走六十英尺 同志们
Sixty feet further, comrades.
接着进入第三排
And three rows in.
在他背上的是什么鬼东西?
What the hell is that on his back?
这是伊凡·克里门托维奇
This here is lvan Klimentovich.
说"你好" 伊凡
Say ''hi,'' lvan.
走那条路 红猴子!
知道了
Gotcha.
伊凡说下面是一个错综复杂的通道网络
lvan says there's a whole network of tunnels down here.
绵延数英里
Goes on for miles.
大家靠紧些
Stay close, everybody.
你最好找对了地方
You better be right about this.
只要我们不分散就没有问题
We'll be all right as long as we don't separate.
火花
Hey, Sparky.
告诉每个人打开他的定位腰带 如果有人看到了什么...
Tell everyone to turn their locator belts on. Anybody sees anything....
我会说"马可"
l'll say ''Marco.''
波罗
Polo.
- 你确信要这么做? - 以一到十的刻度: 二
- Are you sure about this? - On a scale of one to ten: two.
别担心 侦察员小子 她会照顾你的
Don't worry, Boy Scout, she'll take care of you.
她很强的
She's a tough one.
来吧
Come on.
问问你的好友这条路还有多远
Ask your buddy how far this thing goes.
你在我背上怎么样 伊凡?
How you doing up there, lvan?
如果我有腿 我会踢你的屁股
你能帮我抱一会儿吗 他太消极了
Would you mind holding this guy for a while? He is so negative.
那究竟是什么?
What the hell is that?
很大的东西
Something big.
- 莱姆 跟我来 - 好的
- Lime, come with me. - Right.
不 不 停在原地!
No, no, no. Stay put!
站住!
Stop!
你听我说
You listen to me.
听我说!
Listen to me!
我是主管
l'm in charge.
我们现在要往回走 你可以打开那扇门
We're gonna go back. You can take that door apart.
不管那是什么 它正来攻击我们 现在必须得前进
Whatever it is, it's coming for us. Now, we gotta move forward!
莱姆 我们走!
Lime, let's go!
站住!
Stay put!
还有你! 我不怕你!
And you! l am not afraid of you!
我说了算! 我们回去!
l'm in charge! We go back!
我还是死了的好!
糟糕
Oh, crap.
音乐
Music.
真的刺得很深
Really went deep.
你是怎么回事?
Hey, what's wrong with you?!
你杀了我的父亲
You killed my father.
我要杀了你报仇
Your ass is mine.
你笑什么 你这狗娘养的纳粹
What are you laughing at, you Nazi son of a...
想都别想
Don't even think about it.
全都给你 针头脑袋
That's all for you, pinhead.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
- 你在做什么? - 抽一支
- What are you doing? - Having a...
你从不那样点烟
You never light a cigar that way.
你用木制火柴
You use a wooden match.
要保持你的品味 知道吗
Preserves the flavor. You see?
谢谢
Thank you.
所以他认为你我之间...
So he thinks you and l....
那是他对我发火的原因
That's why he's mad at me.
但那不是真的 对吧?
But it's not true, right?
什么?
What?
你知道的 你对我的那种感觉
Well, that, you know, you feel that way about me.
你现在想知道这个?
You want to know that here? Now?
是的
Yeah.
红大个 白大个 不管怎样 男人们都一样
Red, white, whatever. Guys are all the same.
等等我
Hey, wait up.
你找到他们了吗
Have you found them yet?
他们就在我的下面
I got them right below me. It's a matter of minutes.
好的
Okay, good.
可以快一点吗这里怪怪的
Could you hurry up? Because it's a little spooky in here.
丽兹 等等
Liz, wait.
我的上帝
Oh, my God.
慢慢退回去
Let's back out real slow.
迈尔斯 准备好手雷
Myers, ready your grenades.
马可 马可 马可
Marco. Marco. Marco.
赶快挪动你的大红屁股赶过来
Get your big, red butt over here.
我来了 孩子!
l'm coming for you, kid!
不准玩骑肩游戏!
No piggybacks!
下去 你们这些...
Get off me, you...
丽兹 不要去!
Liz, no!
它们会杀掉他 快做点什么!
They're gonna kill him! Do something!
你要我做什么?
What do you want me to do?
- 打我 - 什么?
- Hit me. - What?
打我
Hit me.
快打我!
Now!
你该跑了
You should be running.
他们全部在这里
They are all here.
全部
All of them.
就像所许诺的一样
Just the way it was promised.
这人醒了
This one's awake.
谢谢你带来了这个
Thank you for this.
我看着...
''And l looked...
...看见了一位天使
...and beheld an angel.
在他的右手中 握着打开无底深渊的钥匙
And in his right hand, the key to the bottomless pit.''
我在多博尔斯克的乡下时就听过这句话
These were the words l heard as a peasant boy in Tobolsk.
而现在 这扇门
And now, the door.
通过奥格都·杰哈德送来的门
Sent by the Ogdru Jahad...
他们终于可以来到这世界了
...so that they might at long last enter our world.
你就是那钥匙 就是你那毁灭一切的右手
You are the key, the right hand of doom.
你那只石手
Your stone hand.
你以为那是用来做什么的?
What did you think it was made for?
打开锁
Open the locks.
不要打开 红大个! 不要打开!
Don't do it, Red! Don't do it!
安静
Silence.
想象一下
lmagine it.
一个伊甸园
An Eden...
为你和她而设
...for you and her.
不要
No.
不要?
No?
那就用她的灵魂来交换吧?
ln exchange for her soul, then?
打开那扇门
Open the door.
不
No.
如你所愿
As you wish.
不要!
No!
丽兹!
Liz!
她的灵魂去了另一个世界
Her soul awaits on the other side.
如果你想让她回来
lf you want her back...
打开门
...open the door and claim her.
你的真名就刻在这些枷锁上
Your true name is inscribed around the locks that hold you.
你无法打破它们
You cannot break them...
不管你有多么的强壮
...no matter how strong you are.
月蚀开始了
The eclipse has begun.
你的真名
Your true name...
念出来!
...say it!
成为钥匙
Become the key.
为了她
For her.
阿努·恩·拉玛
Anung un Rama.
再念一遍
Repeat it.
阿努·恩·拉玛
Anung un Rama.
打开最后的锁
Open the final lock.
回想起真正的你!
Remember who you are!
相信我 我活了足够长的岁月来知晓
Believe me, l have lived long enough to know...
为这世界 一滴眼泪也不值得流下
...not a tear will be shed for this world!
你可以选择
You have a choice.
你父亲留给你的
Your father gave you that.
不 你没有选择!
No, you don't!
打开它!
Open it!
快打开它!
Do it!
你做了什么?
What have you done?
我做出了选择
l chose.
你永远无法完成你的宿命了
You will never fulfill your destiny.
你永远不会了解你的真正力量
You will never understand the power inside you.
我会找到方法像这样活下去
l'll just have to find a way to live with that.
孩子
Child.
看看你都干了些什么
Look what you've done.
你杀了我
You've killed me...
一个无足轻重的小人物
...an insignificant man.
但你却带来了
But you have brought forth...
神
...a god.
迈尔斯 快走
Myers, let's go.
地狱对我们来说没有什么
Hell will hold no surprises for us.
我拿了手雷腰环
l took a grenade belt.
这该死的东西坏了
The damn thing's broken.
保护她 好吗
Keep her safe, will you?
不管发生了什么 不要离开她
Whatever happens, don't leave her alone.
我不会离开她的
l won't.
你很好 迈尔斯
You're okay, Myers.
留在这里
Stick around.
红大个
Hey, Red.
拉开导线就行了
Just pull the cable.
我从没怪过你
l didn't get you anything.
你独自一人能应付吗
Are you going to be okay alone?
它能有多厉害?
How big can it be?
该死!
Damn!
真该死
Damn.
这会很痛
Oh, this is gonna hurt.
明早醒来时都会觉得疼
Gonna be sore in the morning.
她没有脉搏
She's got no pulse.
也没有呼吸
She's not breathing.
丽兹?
Liz?
我真笨
l was so foolish.
红大个
Red.
在黑暗中
ln the dark...
我听到你的声音
...l heard your voice.
你说了什么?
What did you say?
我说 嗨
l said, ''Hey...
在那个世界中的你
...you on the other side...
让她自由
...let her go.
因为
Because for...
为了她我会过来
For her l'll cross over.
那时你就会后悔了
And then you'll be sorry.''
是什么使一个人成为真正的男人?
What makes a man a man?
以前我的一个朋友曾经思考过这个问题
A friend of mine once wondered.
是一个人的出身 还是他的生存方式?
Is it his origins? The way he comes to life?
我认为都不是
I don't think so.
我认为是他所做出的选择
It's the choices he makes.
不是他选择怎样去开始
Not how he starts things...
而是他选择怎样去结束
...but how he decides to end them.
大家去哪儿了？我还在这儿
Hey, guys? l'm still here.
有人在吗？
Hello?